Von Tilzer / Gumm Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Legal Papers (Box 53-63)
  - Harry Von Tilzer Music Publishing Co. (HVTMPC), 1903-1956 (Box 55-63)
    - Litigation: HVTMPC vs. the following:
      - Jerry Vogel Music Co., et al
        - Trial documents
          - Briefs from plaintiffs (Box-folder 60/6)
          - Briefs from plaintiffs-appellees (Box-folder 60/7)
          - Copyright and royalty information on disputed songs (Box-folder 60/8)
          - Depositions of Brandenburg, Minnie (Box-folder 60/9)
          - Depositions of Dillon, William A. (Box-folder 60/10)
          - Depositions of Dody, Daniel (Box-folder 60/11)
          - Depositions of Freidberg, Sidney (Box-folder 60/12)
          - Depositions of Nizer, Louis (Box-folder 60/13)
          - Depositions of Rosenbloom, Milton M. (Box-folder 60/14)
          - Depositions of Ryan, Ben (Box-folder 60/15)
          - Depositions of Tafuri, Jennie A. Browne (Box-folder 60/16)
          - Depositions of Vogel, Jerry (Box-folder 60/17)
          - Depositions of Von Tilzer, Harry [summary] (Box-folder 60/18)
          - Examinations before trial: Sterling, Andrew B. Jerry Vogel Music Co., by Jerry Vogel (Box-folder 60/19)
          - Examinations before trial: March 1941 (Box-folder 61/1)
          - Examinations before trial: April 1941 (Box-folder 61/2)
          - Examinations before trial: May 1941 (Box-folder 61/3)
          - Examinations before trial: June 1941 (Box-folder 61/4)
          - Examinations before trial: Von Tilzer, Harry (Box-folder 61/5)
          - Findings of fact and conclusions of law (Box-folder 61/6)
          - Hearing transcript, 1951, (2 folders) (Box-folder 61/7-8)
          - Interlocutory decree (Box-folder 61/9)
          - Judgment (Box-folder 61/10)
          - Judgment of appeal (Box-folder 61/11)
          - Memoranda from defendant (Box-folder 62/1)
          - Memoranda from plaintiff, (3 folders) (Box-folder 62/2-4)
          - Notice of settlement (Box-folder 62/5)
          - Notice to produce (Box-folder 62/6)
          - Opinion (Box-folder 62/7)
          - Order to show cause (Box-folder 62/8)
          - Plaintiff reply to counterclaims (Box-folder 62/9)
          - Pleadings (Box-folder 62/10)
          - Report of special master (Box-folder 62/11)
          - Statements from Von Tilzer, Jules (Box-folder 62/12)
          - Statements from Von Tilzer, Will (Box-folder 62/13)
          - Stenographers' fees (Box-folder 62/14)
          - Stipulation (Box-folder 62/15)
          - Summons and complaint (3 drafts), (3 folders) (Box-folder 62/16-18)
          - Tender of proof (Box-folder 62/19)
          - Miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box-folder 62/20-21)
    - Litigation: William A. Dillon vs Harry Von Tilzer Music Publishing Corp. (Box-folder 63/1)
    - Litigation between Broadway Music Corp. vs Jerry Vogel Music Co. and Jack Norworth (Box-folder 63/2)
    - Litigation between Broadway Music Corp. vs Jerry Vogel Music Co. and Adella & Harold Singer (Box-folder 63/3)
    - Litigation between Rose Druckerman et al vs James G. Harbord et al (Box-folder 63/4)
    - Litigation between Charles K. Harris vs Ted Snyder Co. et al (Box-folder 63/5)
    - Litigation between Edward B. Marks Music Corp. vs Jerry Vogel Music Co. (Box-folder 63/6)
    - Litigation between Selwyn & Co., Inc., vs Bayard Veiller (Box-folder 63/7)
    - Litigation between Shapiro, Bernstein & Co. vs P. F. Collier & Son Co. & Joseph P. McEvoy (Box-folder 63/8)
    - Litigation between M. Witmark & Sons vs Fred Fisher Music Co. et al (Box-folder 63/9)
  - H. Harold Gumm, 1903-1951 (Box 63)
    Contains certificates to practice law, contracts, deed to Los Angeles property, and wills prepared for various clients.
    The wills are arranged alphabetically by name.
    - Certificates to practice law (Box-folder 63/10)
    - Contracts between H. Harold Gumm and Sig Herzig (Box-folder 63/11)
    - Contracts between H. Harold Gumm and Frank Lewis (Box-folder 63/12)
    - Contracts between H. Harold Gumm and Leo Morrison (Box-folder 63/13)
    - Contracts between H. Harold Gumm and Will and Jules Von Tilzer (Box-folder 63/14)
    - Contract between Gertrude S. Gumm (Mrs. H. Harold) and Eugene Berton (Box-folder 63/15)
    - Deed (Los Angeles property), 1948 (Box-folder 63/16)
    - Will prepared for Samuel (Sammy Lee) Levy (Box-folder 63/17)
    - Will prepared for Antonio L. DeMarco (Box-folder 63/18)
    - Will prepared for Mann Holiner (Box-folder 63/19)
    - Will prepared for Catherine Roth (Box-folder 63/20)
    - Will prepared for Lester A. Santly (Box-folder 63/21)
    - Will prepared for Lillian Roth Scott (Lillian Roth) (Box-folder 63/22)
    - Will prepared for Esther Solomon (Esther Santly) (Box-folder 63/23)
- Financial Papers, 1899-1957 (Box 64-69; OV 1, 3-4)
  Contains the financial papers of Harry Von Tilzer, the Estate of Harry Von Tilzer, Harry Von Tilzer Music Publishing Co., Jules Von Tilzer, H. Harold Gumm, and Goldie & Gumm. Includes royalty statements, business and personal financial records, insurance records, and tax records.
  Arranged according to name of originator.
  - Harry Von Tilzer
    - Check stubs, 1931-1938; 1939-1945 (Box-folder 64/1-2)
    - Receipts (Box-folder 64/3)
    - Record of deposits and withdrawals, 1944 (Box-folder 64/4)
    - Royalty statements for Feist & Frankenthaler (Box-folder 64/5)
    - Royalty statements M. Witmark & Sons (Box OV 3)
    - Taxes, 1928, 1940-1945 (Box-folder 64/6)
  - Estate of Harry Von Tilzer
    - Memos, summaries, etc. (Box-folder 64/7)
    - Royalty statements for Bourne, Inc. (Box-folder 64/8)
    - Royalty statements for Broadway Music Corp. (Box-folder 64/9)
    - Royalty statements for Shapiro, Bernstein & Co. (Box-folder 64/10)
    - Estate taxes (Box-folder 64/11)
    - Income taxes (New York and U.S.), 1946-1951 (Box-folder 64/12)
    - Social security taxes (Box-folder 64/13)
    - Freeport House, L. I.--Insurance (Box-folder 65/1)
    - Freeport House, L. I.--Inventory (Box-folder 65/2)
    - Freeport House, L. I.--Maintenance, 1944-1956 (Box-folder 65/3)
    - Freeport House, L. I.--Mortgages, 1908-1930 (Box-folder 65/4)
    - Freeport House, L. I.--Paid bills, 1946-1957 (Box-folder 65/5)
    - Freeport House, L. I.--Taxes, 1930-1956, (2 folders) (Box-folder 65/6)
    - Freeport House, L. I.--Title and title search, appraisal (Box-folder 65/7)
  - Harry Von Tilzer Music Publishing Company
    - ASCAP royalty distributions - Accounts, 1952-1957 (Box-folder 66/1)
    - ASCAP royalty distributions - Statements, 1934-1950 (Box-folder 66/2)
    - ASCAP writer-performance record, 1949-1956 (Box-folder 66/3)
    - Bankruptcy proceedings: Correspondence and notes (Box-folder 66/4)
    - Bankruptcy proceedings: Documents, (2 folders) (Box-folder 66/5-6)
    - Financial reports, 1923-1924 (Box-folder 66/7)
    - General ledger balance book, 1923-1924 (Box-folder 66/8)
    - Insurance, 1944-1949 (Box-folder 66/9)
    - Inventory of safe, 1946 (Box-folder 66/10)
    - Ledger of mechanical releases, 1918-1922 (Box-folder 66/11)
    - List of broadcast uses (by song), 1943-1946 (Box-folder 66/12)
    - List of synchronization uses, 1938-1951 (Box-folder 66/13)
    - Mechanical royalties ledger, 1924-1928 (Box OV 1)
    - Printing order book, 1935-1943 (Box-folder 66/14)
    - Order book (carbon); entries include name and address, quantity and title ordered, and date, 1922-1924 (Box OV 3-4)
    - Federal and state income taxes, 1918-1951, (4 folders) (Box-folder 67/1-4)
    - Employer's tax returns, 1937-1942 (Box-folder 67/5)
  - Jules Von Tilzer
    - Paid bills (Box-folder 67/6)
    - Social security, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 67/7)
    - Federal and state taxes (incomplete), 1948-1954 (Box-folder 67/8)
  - H. Harold Gumm
    - Bank statements, 1941-1944 (Box-folder 67/9)
    - Deposit receipts and cancelled checks, 1941-1944 (Box-folder 67/10)
    - Insurance: Correspondence, bills, etc., (2 folders) (Box-folder 67/11-12)
    - Insurance: Policies (health, auto, etc.) (Box-folder 67/13)
    - Investments: Broker statements, correspondence, 1936-1940 (Box-folder 68/1)
    - Paid bills (correspondence, receipts), 1926-1957, undated (Box-folder 68/2-6)
    - Record of deposits and withdrawals, 1941-1942, 1945 (Box-folder 68/7)
    - Record of expenditures regarding producing activities, 1942 (Box-folder 68/8)
    - Savings books and check registers, 1912, 1921, 1935-1936 (Box-folder 68/9)
    - Taxes, 1942, 1946 (Box-folder 68/10)
  - Goldie & Gumm
    - Accounts payable and receivable (Box-folder 69/1)
    - Inventory of furniture (Box-folder 69/2)
    - Paid bills, 1949-1952, (2 folders) (Box-folder 69/3-4)
    - Taxes, 1946-1953 (Box-folder 69/5-7)
- Catalog of the Harry Von Tilzer Music Publishing Co. (Box 69, 73)
  Contains printed, typescript, and index cards; printed catalog; list of works published by HVTMPC; copyright information; status of catalog as of 1957, etc. Mostly undated material.
  - HVTMPC printed catalogs, some annotated with copyright information (Box-folder 69/6)
  - Status of HVTMPC catalog as of July 1957 (typescript) (Box-folder 69/7)
  - Lists of Harry Von Tilzer works published by HVTMPC (Box-folder 69/8)
  - List of Harry Von Tilzer works published by others (Box-folder 69/9)
  - Songs published by HVTMPC - ASCAP list (Box-folder 69/10)
  - Songs published by HVTMPC - Revision of ASCAP list (Box-folder 69/11)
  - Copyright information for HVTMPC catalog (typescript) (Box-folder 69/12)
  - Copyright renewal applications [for seven songs] (Box-folder 69/13)
  - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 69/14)
  - Card file labelled "not in current catalogue", Contains 3 x 5 cards listing song titles, authors of words, composers, and copyright date. (Box 73)
- Programs, 1894-1929, 1940 (Box 69)
  Printed programs and newsprint announcements, primarily about Harry Von Tilzer performances or compositions.
  - 1894-1906 (Box-folder 69/15)
  - 1909-1929, 1940, undated (Box-folder 69/16)
- Photographs (Box 70, OV 2)
  Includes both publicity and casual photos of Harry Von Tilzer and family members. There is also a collection of performers' publicity photos. Mostly undated material.
  - Harry Von Tilzer alone see also Box OV 2 (8 oversize folders and 1 wooden mounting) (Box-folder 70/1)
  - Harry Von Tilzer with others see also Box OV 2 (1 wooden mounting) (Box-folder 70/2)
  - Others, including family members see also Box OV 2 (2 buttons) (Box-folder 70/3)
  - Male performers (identified and unidentified), (2 folders) (Box-folder 70/4-5)
  - Female performers (identified and unidentified), (2 folders) (Box-folder 70/6-7)
  - Groups of performers (identified and unidentified), (2 folders) (Box-folder 70/8-9)
  - Child performers (Box-folder 70/10)
  - Banquet camera photographs (rolled) of ASCAP meeting and dinner at the Ritz-Carlton Hotel, March 30, 1927; and ASCAP meeting and dinner at the Ritz-Carlton Hotel, March 27, 1930 (Box OV 2)
- Clippings, 1900-1959 (Box 71-72)
  Arranged by subject (as originally ordered) or by decade.
  - Harry Von Tilzer (writings, biographical material, obituaries) (Box-folder 71/1)
  - Obituary notices for William V. Goldie (Box-folder 71/2)
  - Notices regarding Dolph Singer (Box-folder 71/3)
  - Articles on estate settlements (Box-folder 71/4)
  - 1900-1909 (Box-folder 71/5)
  - 1920-1929, (2 folders) (Box-folder 71/6-7)
  - 1930-1939, (3 folders) (Box-folder 71/8-10)
  - 1940-1949, (3 folders) (Box-folder 72/1-3)
  - 1950-1959, (2 folders); The following complete issues were also included, but had crumbled beyond legibility: The Billboard (Special souvenir issue, 1894-1950; Sept. 2, 1957) New York Daily News (April 16, 1948) Variety (July 31, 1957; Oct. 9, 1957; Oct. 23, 1957; TV film commercials produced since Jan. 1, 1957). (Box-folder 72/4-5)
- Miscellany (Box 70, OV 1)
  Miscellaneous artwork, publicity, publications. Mostly undated.
  - Artwork
    - Cartoons: "Birth of a Song" by Paul Carruth and Joseph R. Fliesler (signed) and "Seems Like Yesterday" by C. Kessler (Box OV 1)
    - Placemats - "Claytoon" illustrations of Harry Von Tilzer songs from a series entitled "The Gay Nineties" by the Sass-Dorne Studios of Hollywood, California (Box OV 1)
    - Wooden mounting of clipping from The Philadelphia Inquirer, July 30, 1939, illustrating "She's Only a Bird in a Gilded Cage" with slides from an early nickelodeon accompaniment of the song (Box OV 1)
  - Publicity - HVTMPC
    - "A Tribute to Harry Von Tilzer", Printed flyer (Box-folder 70/11)
    - List of on-air plugs, 1936-1939 (Box-folder 70/12)
    - Notes for "The Silver Anniversary of the Silver Haired Composer Harry Von Tilzer", Manuscript, in pencil (Box-folder 70/13)
  - Publications
    - Pamphlets, booklets, flyers, etc. (Box-folder 70/14)
    - Spaeth, Sigmund. Read 'Em and Weep: The Songs You Forgot to Remember. New York/Garden City: Doubleday, Page & Co., 1927. (Box-folder 70/15)
    - Proposal for "The International Ice Frolics", Typewritten, no name or date (Box-folder 70/16)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 70/17)